Jobayed Sumon

Full Stack Software Engineer

I'm a full-stack software engineer with expertise in Laravel, React and Flutter. I've extensive knowledge of databases like MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Firebase, etc. PHP and JavaScript is my comfort language with expertise in algorithm design and data structures.



jobayedahmedsumon@gmail.com

Ohaka-1216, Bangladesh

in linkedin.com/in/jobayedsumon

+8801677242853

jobayedsumon.tech

github.com/jobayedsumon

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelancing

Remote

06/2023 - Present

Currently working on various freelance projects using Laravel, React and Flutter remotely.

Software Engineer

The Wick Firm

05/2022 - 05/2023 Dubai, UAE

It is a digital ad agency based in Dubai where I worked remotely

Achievements/Tasks

- Built NFT tracking dashboard using Laravel and Web3
- Developed dynamic dashboard and websites using Laravel, MySQL and React.is/Next.is
- Developed AI based chatbot and creative ads generator using Python, OpenAI and React.js
- Implementing responsive design and ensuring cross-browser compatibility follwoing figma, adobe xd

Software Engineer

Apsis Solutions Limited

01/2021 - 05/2022 Dhaka, Bangladesh Renowned software company located at Banani, Dhaka

Achievements/Tasks

- Worked on various ERP solutions using React.js/Next.js, PHP/Laravel, Codeigniter
- Developed ERP systems for financial institutes and offices
- Developed mobile apps with Flutter and Node.js API
- Updated existing ERP systems

Web Developer

Virtual Market Solution Limited

06/2020 - 12/2020

Dhaka, Bangladesh

It is an ISO certified IT firm located in Gulshan - 1, Dhaka

- Achievements/TaskBuilt websites with Laravel, jQuery and MySQL
- Built web apps and POS systems for businesses
- Developed APIs for mobile apps
- Upgrade existing websites

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in CSE

Daffodil Institute of Information Technology

01/2016 - 12/2019

3.19 out of 4.00

Courses

 Computer Science and Engineering

SKILLS



PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS

IFIC Bank ERP System Using Next.js and Nest.js (10/2021)

Developed various ERP modules of one of the Bangladesh's top bank IFIC

City Bank ERP System Using PHP Codeigniter (03/2021)

Developed the expense management module of one of the Bangladesh's top bank City bank's core ERP solution using PHP Codeigniter and Oracle

Office ERP System Using Laravel (04/2021)

Worked on various modules of Apsis Solutions Limited's ERP System using Laravel and MuSOI

NFTY Dash - An NFT Tracking Dashboard Using Laravel and Web3 (05/2022)

Developed NFT tracking dashboard from The wick Firm using Laravel and Web3

Funny Way - A Blog Site Using AI Based Image Generation (10/2022)

In A Funny Way is a blog site with AI based image generation using Laravel and React.js with OpenAI

Baladna - Qatar Based Food Company Portfolio Website (11/2022)

Baladna is a Qatar based food company portfolio website built using Laravel and React.js

Aamar Shop E-Commerce Website and API Using Laravel (08/2020)

Built the frontend, admin panel and API of Amar Shop e-commerce website using Laravel and MySQL

Cookie Reward Converter for converting google play balance into real cash (04/2023)

This is a Mobile app made with Flutter and admin panel made with Laravel for converting google play balance into real cash

Office HRM mobile app Employee Module Using Flutter And Laravel (08/2021)

HRM mobile app employee module is for Apsis Solutions Limited's office employee using Flutter, Laravel

Also developed and worked on many E-Commerce (Single & Multi-Vendor), POS System, Inventory management system, Company Portfolio, News Portal etc.

Experienced in integrating various third party APIs into websites and customising them to meet the business needs.